Jeremy Jacobs

624 S Sanders Rd, Birmingham, AL 35226 - 205-492-0990 - jeremy.e.jacobs@gmail.com

Summary

With a 12-year Information Technology career behind me, I am making the transition into software and Web development. I've created business applications using PHP and MySQL at three different companies from 2004 to the present, and I've spent the last year learning the C# language and .NET platform. I have created a small number of C#/.NET applications for my current employer. My ultimate goal is to gain the experience and the knowledge to become a sought-after project manager.

Experience

Technology Manager, LegalCorp Document Services

Jul 2011 - Present

Finding ways to achieve business goals through implementing technology solutions. Website redesign and maintenance. Development and management of PHP/MySQL-based timecard system. Managing technology aspects of litigation support.

TechnologyManager, DocumentTechnologies

Aug 2006 - Jan 2011

Maintained computer hardware and software infrastructure. Created and implemented a PHP/MySQL-based job ticketing system. Managed all aspects of IPRO to prepare documents for litigation software and high-volume printing.

Imaging Deliverables Manager, Discover-e Legal

Sep 2005 - Aug 2006

Prepared digital images of scanned documents for importation into litigation support databases. Managed high-volume printing jobs.

Database Designer, Media Solutions International

Nov 2004 - Feb 2005

Designed and implemented a complete payroll management system using PHP and MySQL. Project was notable for its extremely complicated sales commission structure.

Sole Proprietor, Jacobs Computer Services

Aug 2003 - Nov 2004

Provided customers with a variety of PC hardware and Windows-based software support. Designed, implemented, and managed small business networks. Performed website and graphic design.

Customer Service Tech, Sonitrol Security dba VyaNet

Jun 2000 - Jun 2003

Customer support for dial-up, DSL, wireless, T1, and satellite Internet access. Managed customer domain registration and renewal, hosting, FTP access, FrontPage extensions, and email aliasing in a Red Hat Linux platform. Provided maintenance for company hardware. Created tools to automate information management using PHP and XML.

Skills & Expertise

C#, .NET, Visual Studio, PHP, MySQL, HTML

Education

University of Alabama at Birmingham

2009 - 2013

Will complete my Bachelor of Science in Information Systems in May, 2013.

Courses

Mobile Development IS 491 Project Management MG 417

Systems Analysis IS 321 Intro to Database Management Systems IS 301

Intro to Business Programming IS 204 Programming Logic IS 295

Information Security Management IS 413 Strategic Management BUS 450

International Business MG 415 Intro to Business Intelligence IS 417

Enterprise Systems IS 302 Social Media/Virtual Business Communication IS 491

Quantitative Analysis II QM 215 Quantitative Analysis I QM 214

Interests

3D printing, podcasting, music composition & performing, languages